ldsmag.com 2013-04-03

# Meridian Magazine:: Privacy Policy

  LDSMAG.com (or MeridianMagazine.com or Meridian Magazine) is a Web site for and about members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints and their like-minded friends. We are in no way affiliated with the official Web site of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints (“The Church) or “The Church” itself. We are a private organization and have our own editorial policies. 

We are very sensitive to the privacy of Internet users who visit this site. We endeavor to provide users all information regarding our identity, how we use personal information that is collected, how to contact us, and how they can access and update their personal information. We also inform users of all potential recipients of the personal information. We do not use any personal information for purposes beyond those stated herein. 

**Our Identity and How to Contact Us**

This site is solely owned and operated by Scot and Maurine Proctor. Users can contact us via e-mail at: [feedback@meridianmagazine.com ](mailto:feedback@meridianmagazine.com) or through a regular snail-mail address here: Meridian Magazine 409 N. Country Manor Lane Alpine, UT 84004. Users are welcome to send a message detailing any questions or concerns. 

**Double Opt-In Subscriber Base**

Meridian Magazine's daily e-mail subscription is set up with a double-opt-in policy. When you sign up for our daily send, you will receive a confirmation notice in your e-mail inbox that you must respond to, to become a confirmed subscriber. If you do nothing after you have once signed up for the daily send, over a period of about 96 hours your name and personal information that you gave us will be dropped from our database. With every e-mail you receive a clear way to unsubscribe will be given at the bottom of the send. If you request to be removed from the Meridian Magazine subscriber base (the daily e-mail send), generally your request is automatically updated and handled within 48 hours. 

**Personal Information: Collection and Use**

Personal Data. LDSMAG.COM collects information from readers only on a voluntary basis, if one chooses to sign up for the daily e-mail send, in the following categories (and never discloses the information except as provided herein): first and last name, birth year, gender, postal code and e-mail address. 

Information is provided voluntarily by readers and is used by Meridian Magazine only to the extent necessary to deliver products ordered from Meridian or Meridian Publishing, the Meridian Travel send, to subscribe to the daily e-mail updates, and/or to subscribe to any other e-mail send that may be offered from Meridian Magazine. 

We regard this information as confidential and do not use it for any other purpose, sell it to other parties, or disclose it to any third party (except to third-party delivery services to effectuate delivery of the goods as requested by the user). If any personal information needs to be updated, readers may can contact us at: [support@meridianmagazine.com ](mailto:support@meridianmagazine.com) and request assistance. 

**Other Meridian Affiliated Sites**

LDSMAG.COM (Meridian Magazine) has established other “sister” Websites, including: LDSPRO.COM, LDSGETAWAY.COM, NEWTEMPLES.COM, MERIDIANMAGAZINE.COM/JOSEPH, MERIDIANMAGAZINE.COM/SHARON and uses these sites to promote professional services and resources for Meridian readers. Information gathered from these sites is used strictly to facilitate the user's request or to respond to a question, and for no other purpose.

**Collection and Use of Other Data**

Meridian Magazine will occasionally contract with a third-party service provider to help track and analyze usage and volume statistics on this site. The third-party service provider only collects general summaries of site activities. This information is used only to improve the site's quality. Any time this third-party service uses cookies or clear gifs, neither contain personally identifiable information, and are only used by us to help in tracking and analyzing site usage information. 

**Cookies and Clear Gifs.**

**What Are Cookies?** A cookie is a string of information that a Web site stores on a visitor's computer, and that the visitor's browser provides to the Web site each time the visitor returns. Most major websites use cookies. Because the browser provides this cookie information to the website at each visit, cookies serve as a sort of label that allows a website to "recognize" a browser when it returns to the site. The domain name in Meridian cookies will clearly identify their affiliation with Meridian and, on rare occasion, its third-party service provider. 

**What Are Clear GIFs?** Clear gifs (also known as web beacons) are used in combination with cookies to help web site operators understand how visitors interact with their websites. A clear gif is typically a transparent graphic image (usually 1 pixel x 1 pixel) that is placed on a site. The use of a clear gif allows the site to measure the actions of the visitor opening the page that contains the clear gif. It makes it easer to follow and record the activities of a recognized browser, such as the path of pages visited at a website. Any information gathered from Clear GIFs is strictly for Meridian Magazine's use and only helps determine how we can better serve our readers. 

**You Can Control the Use of Cookies.**

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Meridian visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers by Meridian, its contractors, or third-party service providers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before linking to any of Meridian's Web sites. Certain features of Meridian's Web sites may not function properly without the aid of cookies, such as the Poll (to keep from stuffing the ballot box). 

Internet Protocol (“IP”) Addresses. When users request pages from LDSMAG.COM for printing or to forward on to friends, our servers may log their IP address in order to improve site administration. This information, along with the other information listed above, can also be used to produce usage statistics to help Meridian Magazine better meet the needs of users and determine specific interests. 

**Protecting Information**

LDSMAG.COM states that any information collected from users in the form of names, addresses, e-mail addresses, telephone numbers etc. from use of the ‘Dedicated Sends', ‘Meridian Marketplace', 'Special Announcements', 'Special Offers', 'Advertisements', or other, is used solely for their applicable subject. Such information is stored only by LDSMAG.COM for the purposes of reference related to their subject, and to deliver the service related to their specific subject. Information collected by LDSMAG.COM is not sent to any third-party nor is it collated for any other use than for reference related to their subject, and to deliver the service related to their specific subject. 

Information is stored privately and is not publicly accessible. LDSMAG.COM takes reasonable steps to ensure that this is the case for protecting information regarding users. 

If you wish to correct or update any information given to LDSMAG.COM (Meridian Magazine) regarding yourself, please use [feedback@meridianmagazine.com ](mailto:feedback@meridianmagazine.com) or feel free to contact us via snail-mail as noted above: Meridian Magazine 409 N. Country Manor Lane Alpine, UT 84004.

For critical issues or emergencies, please call Meridian Magazine at 202-714-5775.

LDSMAG.COM reserves the right to update this privacy policy in the future, and accepts that users should periodically check this privacy policy to be aware of revisions. Meridian Magazine understands that continued use of its services signifies that its users accept the terms of its privacy policy. 

**Foreign Transfer of Data**

This site is optimally designed for use by U.S., Canadian, Australian, New Zealand and U.K. residents. If you are not a resident of one of these countries, you can, of course, use this site, but you are solely responsible for making sure that your actions comply with the laws in your area. When you submit information through this Web site, we understand that your action is an affirmative act, indicating informed consent to the processing as well as informed consent to allow the trans border transfer of the data to the U.S. for the purposes outlined above. If you submit any personal information about yourself or others, you alone are responsible for the consequences of making this transfer of personal information. 

**Children's Privacy**

We do not knowingly collect information from children under 13. Children under 13 wishing to submit personal information to the site are advised to have their parents submit any requests using the parents' own personal data. 

**Third-Party Links**

LDSMAG.COM links with numerous third-party vendors and sites and declares that it is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of any of these third-party sites. For your own protection, you should review the policies of similar sites to ensure they meet your personal expectations of privacy. 

**Future Changes to Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions of the Privacy Policy at any time. As we do not typically use personal information except as provided for above, we are not in a position to notify each user of material changes in our Privacy Policy. We encourage you to check the Privacy Policy to remain informed of any changes. 

**Current Effective Date**

This current updated version of the Privacy Policy became effective on the 1st day of January, 2011.
